DIEGO RESTREPO

2938 Somersworth Ct, Orlando, FL, 32835 (407) 272-5729

dieres2010@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

Professional Summary

Systematic Software Engineer with 16 years of software engineering experience for Health Care companies.

Enthusiastic Software Engineer eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Clear understanding of Developing and Design and training in Software Development. Motivated to learn, grow, and excel in this Industry

Skills

- React
- NoSql
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Mongoose
- MongoDB
- IndexedDB
- Mysql
- APIs
- Moment.is
- Jquery
- Javascript
- CSS
- HTML
- Data Management
- Installation and maintenance
- Data Migration Between Informix, Oracle, SQL Server and Sybase Databases
- Experience in Store Procedures Language (SPL)
- Informix 4GL specialist
- Some experience in Power Builder and C# programming
- Database designing
- Software designing
- Advanced problem-solving skills
- Troubleshooting and debugging

- User requirements
- Testing and debugging
- Innovative
- Performance and scalability optimization
- Fast learner

Projects

Git Pokemon | https://github.com/dieres2010/Pokemon-App.git

Application that allows to find which Pokémon are you based on how many repositories you have in GitHub. You get the most powerful Pokémon based in the number of repositories you have.

Built Using: Javascript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Pokemon and GiyHub API's

Deployed URL: https://mikeydgithub.github.io/Pokemon-App/

Loan Me A Home | https://github.com/dieres2010/loanMeAHome.git

Allows mortgage lenders to add their home loans with application link so home buyers can choose the loan that fits their buying criteria.

Built Using: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, HandelBars

Deployed URL: https://loanmeahome.herokuapp.com/

DevHub | https://github.com/dieres2010/DevHub.git

An app giving users a way to choose and design their ecommerce, landing page, portfolios, image hosting, social media, or business page. It's a one stop shop where you can sign up and see the ranges of website template you want created for you. Also links you with the developer of your choice to team up and get your vision created.

Built Using: JavaScript, React, NoSQL databases, GraphQL APIs, MERN, Chakra UI

Deployed URL: https://whispering-island-67364.herokuapp.com/

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Developer, Coding Bootcamp, 2022, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering, 1998, Universidad Antonio Nariño, Medellin, Colombia.

Associate of Science Software, Software Writer, 1995, Politecnico Colombiano Jaime Isaza Cadavid, Medellin, Colombia.

Work History

Remodeling Services, January 2011 Self-Employed, Orlando, Florida, U.S.A.

• Flooring, Painting, Kitchen and Bathroom Remodeling.

Applications Coordinator, February 2007 to December 2010, **Servinte S.A.** Medellin, Colombia

- Determine customer requirements.
- Perform requirements analysis.
- Develop application designs
- Give Support to other areas.
- Study and identify the technical and functional applications for customers.
- Support the replication and / or quality control solution.
- Planning the new features in new versions to release.
- Lead projects on designated applications.
- Perform planning and control of projects
- Identify risks and propose action plans for improvement.
- Provide leadership in design and development.
- Resolve doubts to Programmers.
- Make estimates of developments for quotation.
- Identify training needs in the organization.
- Plan and execute training plans.
- Develop and / or approve documentation.
- Answer questions to other functional areas.
- Make presentations.
- Perform functional tests
- Perform disclosure of customer versions.
- Participate in project meetings.
- Suggest ways of improving the organization.

Back Liner, February 2005 to February 2007, **Servinte S.A.** Medellin, Colombia

- Give Internal support to areas in technical terms both internal and external customer.
- Analyze difficult cases that other areas have failed to resolve.
- Create and Manage Stored Procedures, Triggers and Functions in Informix, SQL Server and Oracle.
- Optimize Queries to improve the response time of the programs.
- Write procedures for migrating applications.
- Migrate Data between Informix, Oracle, SQL server and Sybase Databases.
- Advise on Database connection.
- Analize and Resolve errors.

Senior Programmer, February 2002 to February 2005, **Servinte S.A.** Medellin, Colombia

- Coordinate and assist analysts in the maintenance and development of the applications
- Advise on best practices in programming, most optimal SQL statements, lessons learned.
- Give support in the analysis of the solutions to the quality controls on programs.
- Review the designs against the technical (language, database, etc.).
- Ensure compliance with resolution times and quality control and programming standards.
- Design of new features.
- Installation, training, and support to customers.

Programmer, February 1995 to February 2002, **Servinte S.A.** Medellin, Colombia

- Analysis and development of programs under Informix 4GL RDS.
- Write necessary SQL queries on the programs.
- Create the SQL statements for the modification of the database (New or Modified Tables or Indexes)

Certifications

- IBM AS-400
- Power Builder
- Full Stack Web Developer